Guide to the Henry Lewis Stimson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Special Subjects, Series IV
  - Republican Party, 1894-1904
    - List of contributors to the 27th Assembly District Republican Club Campaign Committee, 1904 (Box 194, Folder 11)
    - Rules and Constitutions of Republican Organizations, [1897-1904?] (Box 194, Folder 12)
  - Republican Party, 1910
    - Republican State Convention including list of delegates, 1910 (Box 194, Folder 13)
    - 1910 Campaign--John A. Dix's Connection in the Wall Paper Combination, memos, notes (Box 194, Folder 14)
    - 1910 Campaign--Reference material regarding Judge Alton Parker and his connection with the Ulster County Bank Incident, reference material on Jotham B. Allds (Box 194, Folder 15)
    - 1910 Campaign--Material used in support of Frank N. Williams for State Engineer and Surveyor, includes testimony in case of The People vs. Frederick Skene (Box 194, Folder 16)
    - 1910 Campaign--References and notes regarding Labor (Box 194, Folder 17)
    - Notes, memos, information regarding issues that might be raised in the campaign for Governor, 1910 (Box 194, Folder 18)
    - Notes and report regarding the legislative sessions, 1910 (Box 194, Folder 19)
    - Historic review of the legislative sessions, 1910 (Box 194, Folder 20)
    - Campaign for Governor, miscellaneous reference material, 1910 (Box 194, Folder 21)
    - Campaign--itineraries, 1910 (Box 194, Folder 22)
    - Copies of statements made in support of Stimson for Governor, 1910 (Box 194, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence of others relating to the Gubernatorial campaign, 1910 October-November (Box 195, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous printed campaign publicity, 1910 (Box 195, Folder 2)
    - Republican pamphlets in the Stimson campaign for Governor, 1910 (Box 195, Folder 3)
    - Democratic Party pamphlets in New York campaign of 1910 (Box 195, Folder 4)
    - Lists of possible supporters and of those who have given assistance in campaign of 1910 (Box 195, Folder 5)
    - Mailing lists used in the campaign of 1910 (Box 195, Folder 6)
    - Campaign financial records including statement of treasurer of political committee, statement of receipts and expenditures, 1910 (Box 195, Folder 7)
    - Campaign ledger of financial memos by George R. Carter, 1910 (Box 195, Folder 8)
    - Campaign of 1910--bills, receipts, deposit tickets, and other miscellaneous financial records (Box 195, Folder 9)
    - 1910 campaign--miscellaneous handwritten notes (Box 195, Folder 10)
    - Bank of North America, Dummy Loans regarding campaign attack by the New York Evening Post and O.G. Villard, 1910 December (Box 195, Folder 11)
  - Republican Party, 1913-1920
    - Meeting at the Republican Club, 1913 May 23 (Box 195, Folder 12)
    - Three drafts for the Republican Platform for the campaign of 1913, 1913 July (Box 195, Folder 13)
    - Minutes of meeting held to discuss the work to be done at the Republican Conference Dec 5, 1913 December 3 (Box 195, Folder 14)
    - Notes and research material on matters to be discussed at the Republican Conference Dec 5, Circa 1913 December 3 (Box 195, Folder 15)
    - Conference of New York State Republicans, 1913 December 5-1914 May 28 (Box 195, Folder 16-17)
    - Root committee to draft a platform on the attitude of the Republican party on New York Constitutional amendments, the Committee of 30, 1914 June (Box 195, Folder 18)
    - Letters to Lafayette Gleason regarding serving on Root committee, 1914 July (Box 195, Folder 19)
    - Committee of 31 on Platform, minutes of meeting, 1914 July 24 (Box 195, Folder 20)
    - Committee of 30, minutes of meeting of the Subcommittee of 9 on Platform, 1914 July 24 (Box 195, Folder 21)
    - Committee of 30, drafts of platform in matter of constitutional amendments for presentation to the New York Republican Convention, 1914 July 27-August 19 (Box 196, Folder 1)
    - Republican Party, unidentified, 1914-1915 (Box 196, Folder 2)
    - Campaign to nominate Elihu Root as Republican Presidential Candidate, 1915 December-1916 June (Box 196, Folder 3)
    - Republican National Convention, Chicago, 1916 June (Box 196, Folder 4)
    - Republican presidential campaign, 1916 June-November (Box 196, Folder 5)
    - New York State Republican draft platform, 1920 February (Box 196, Folder 6)
    - National Republican campaign, 1920 April-October (Box 196, Folder 7-8)
  - Early Legal Career
    - Notebook: Harvard Law School, [1888-1889] (Box 197, Folder 1)
    - Legal notes and memoranda: early career (Box 197, Folder 2-6)
  - A System of Corporation Law: contract outline, memo for George Wharton Pepper, Henry Lewis Stimson outlines, drafts and notes, 1893 (Box 197, Folder 7-8)
  - United States Attorney
    - Courtroom notes in case of United States vs. American Sugar Refining, 1906 (Box 197, Folder 9)
    - United States vs. Delaware, Lakawana and Western Railroad Company, court memoranda, 1906-1907 (Box 197, Folder 10)
    - United States vs. New York Central and Hudson River Railroad, Nathan Guilford, Fred L. Pomeroy, court memoranda, 1907 (Box 197, Folder 11)
    - United States vs. Western Transit Company, indictment, 1907 May 1 (Box 197, Folder 12)
    - United States vs. New York, Ontario and Western Railway Company, indictment, 1907 May 7 (Box 197, Folder 13)
    - United States vs. Fritz Augustus Heinze, 1907 December (Box 197, Folder 14)
    - United States vs. Press Publishing Company, United States vs. Caleb M. Van Hamm, indictments, 1909 January (Box 198, Folder 1)
    - Prosecution of the American Sugar Refining Company, 1909-1912 (Box 198, Folder 2)
    - United States vs. Atlas Portland Cement, memo, 1921 June 2 (Box 198, Folder 3)
    - Charts for counsel to Cement Manufacturers Protective Association (Box 198, Folder 4-5)
    - Memoranda regarding Federal Receiverships, 1924 (Box 198, Folder 6)
  - Bar Associations, 1892-1928
    - Correspondence of others pertaining to the Association of the Bar and the Committee on the Amendment of the Law, includes also minutes of committee meeting, 1892 October 18-1893 February 4 (Box 198, Folder 7)
    - Minutes, meetings of the House Committee of the Bar Association, 1897 February 4-November 5 (Box 198, Folder 8)
    - Minutes of special meeting of the Bar Association Committee on the Amendment of the Law, 1904 February 20 (Box 198, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence of others concerning the Judiciary Committee of the Bar Association of the City of New York, 1909 May-November (Box 198, Folder 10)
    - Annual Reports of the Judiciary Committee of the New York City Association of the Bar, 1911-1912 (Box 198, Folder 11)
    - Committee on Character and Fitness of the New York State Bar Association, 1923 December-1924 May (Box 198, Folder 12)
    - New York State Bar Association: Committee on the Salary of Federal Judges, 1924 (Box 198, Folder 13)
    - Committee on the Judiciary of the New York State Bar Association, 1924-1927 (Box 198, Folder 14-16)
    - New York State Bar Association and Bar Association of the City of New York, correspondence of others, reference material, reports, and miscellaneous other papers, 1921-1925, undated (Box 199, Folder 1)
    - Association of the Bar of the City of New York, reports of Committees on the Constitutional Convention, 1938 (Box 199, Folder 2)
    - New York County Lawyers' Association: Minutes of Board of Directors meetings, 1921-1924 (Box 199, Folder 3-4)
    - New York County Lawyers' Association: Committee on Professional Ethics and various other committees (Box 199, Folder 5)
  - Ballinger-Pinchot controversy
    - Briefs and memos prepared for defense of Gifford Pinchot at Joint Investigation of the Department of the Interior and Forestry Service, 1910 February-March (Box 199, Folder 6)
    - Notes prepared by Henry Lewis Stimson for defense of Gifford Pinchot at Joint Investigation of the Department of the Interior and Forestry Service, 1910 February-March (Box 199, Folder 7)
    - Reference documents for testimony of Gifford Pinchot before Joint Investigation of the Department of the Interior and Forestry Service, 1910 February-March (Box 199, Folder 8)
    - Engineering News, article regarding Secretary Ballinger and the Reclamation Service document 51, 1910 January 13 (Box 199, Folder 9)
    - Documents received as enclosures in letters from Charles E. Kelley (Box 199, Folder 10)
    - Reference documents--copy of Aug 11, 1909 message, Glavis to Taft with exhibits and Glavis summary (Box 199, Folder 11)
    - Statement by James R. Garfield and reference materials mentioned therein for testimony before Joint Investigation of the Department of Interior and the Forestry Service, 1910 March (Box 200, Folder 1)
    - Memo based on information from Layman regarding charges against Colter in service of general land office [Used in defense of Gifford Pinchot?] (Box 200, Folder 2)
    - Reference material for Gifford Pinchot defense, report and summary of the Attorney General regarding the Interior Department and the Cunningham Coal-Lands Claims, 1909 September 11 (Box 200, Folder 3)
    - Reference material for Gifford Pinchot's defense. Senate Document 248--Presidential message in response to Senate Resolution no. 112 of Dec 21, 1910 (Box 200, Folder 4)
  - Waterpower and public lands policy
    - Notes regarding waterpower and public lands policy, [1909-1910?] (Box 200, Folder 5)
    - Philip Wells to John H. Small, one enclosure, reference material regarding waterpower and public lands policy, 1909 October 16 (Box 200, Folder 6)
    - Policy of the Forest Service as to permits for power plants in National Forest, Introductory memorandum and Exhibits 1-12, 1908 April 20 (Box 200, Folder 7-10)
    - Reference material: U.S. Department of Agriculture, Forest Service circulars nos. 143, 144, 1908 March (Box 200, Folder 11)
    - Philip Wells to John H. Small, reference material regarding waterpower, 1909 October 16 (Box 200, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous reference material regarding waterpower policy (Box 200, Folder 13)
    - "Control by Congress of Waterpower developed in navigable waters of the U.S." by Edward Burling, enclosure in John F. Bass to Henry Lewis Stimson, 1909 November 18 (Box 201, Folder 1)
    - Enclosures in W. J. Mangan to Henry Lewis Stimson, 1909 November 29 (Box 201, Folder 2)
    - Reference material sent to Henry Lewis Stimson by John F. Bass, Circa 1910 January 19 (Box 201, Folder 3)
  - National Conservation Association
    - National Conservation Association, 1910-1912 (Box 201, Folder 4-5)
    - National Conservation Association, printed circulars, 1909-1911 (Box 201, Folder 6)
    - National Conservation Association, 1913-1914 (Box 201, Folder 7)
  - Mortgage tax bills, 1903-1905
    - Proposed New York State Mortgage Tax Bill, 1903 (Box 201, Folder 8)
    - Proposed New York State Bill to amend the tax law in relation to the taxation of debts secured by mortgages, 1905 (Box 201, Folder 9)
  - Reform movements
    - Good Government Club, 1895 (Box 201, Folder 10)
    - Charity Organization Society, 1898 (Box 201, Folder 10)
    - Committee of Fourteen, 1909 June-1913 (Box 201, Folder 11)
    - Committee on Safety and related reference material on fire prevention, 1911 (Box 201, Folder 12)
    - Citizens' Municipal Committee, 1913 (Box 201, Folder 13)
    - New York Short Ballot Organization and pamphlets from other Short Ballot groups, [1913-1915] (Box 201, Folder 14)
    - Woman Suffrage, Anti-Woman Suffrage pamphlets, circulars, 1913-1914 (Box 201, Folder 15)
  - War Department, 1911-1913
    - Notes from talk with Governor Colton of Puerto Rico during trip to Panama and the West Indies, 1911 July (Box 202, Folder 1)
    - Notes regarding personnel on trip to Panama, 1911 (Box 202, Folder 2)
    - Taft drafts of veto messages of the Tariff Bill and the Wool Bill with annotations in the hand of Henry Lewis Stimson, 1911 August (Box 202, Folder 3)
    - Financial records from inspection trip of the Western United States, 1911 September-October (Box 202, Folder 4)
    - Regarding House Resolution 208 and the hearings before the House Committee on Expenditures of the War Department, 1911-1912 (Box 202, Folder 5)
    - Notes by Henry Lewis Stimson on the Army Appropriations Bill and the effect of its provisions, [1912 Jan] (Box 202, Folder 6)
    - Analysis by the War Department of appropriations within the various appropriation bills for the Army, 1912 (Box 202, Folder 7)
    - Letter to James Hay, statement of views on proposed legislation contained in committee draft of Army Appropriations Bill, printed copy only, 1912 January 4 (Box 202, Folder 8)
    - Letter to the speaker of the House of Representatives regarding Distribution of the Mobile Army of the United States, printed copy only, 1912 January 25 (Box 202, Folder 9)
    - Army Appropriations Bill, notes on legislative committees and on progress of the bill, 1912 January-February (Box 202, Folder 10)
    - Memo of Enoch Crowder's Objections to the Army Appropriations Bill, [1912 January-Feb?] (Box 202, Folder 11)
    - Memoramda regarding objections to provisions in the Army Appropriations Bill affecting army organization and administration reported in Conferences Report of May 27, 1912, 1912 April-May (Box 202, Folder 12)
    - House of Representatives Report 508, part 2 only. Typed script of printed document of May 10, 1912. Minority Report--relief of the Adjutant General of the Army from the duties of his office. (Box 202, Folder 13)
    - Memorandum of sequence of events mailed to Robert J. Bulkley regarding the Army Appropriations Bill, 1912 May 30 (Box 202, Folder 14)
    - Memorandum of Objections to the Army Appropriations Bill as reported by the conferees, sent to Senator Hoke Smith, 1912 June 1 (Box 202, Folder 15)
    - Henry Lewis Stimson draft for Taft veto of the Army Appropriations Bill, 1912 June [15] (Box 202, Folder 16)
    - Memorandum on Army Appropriations Bill, 1912 July 25 (Box 202, Folder 17)
    - "Report on the Organization of the Land Forces of the United States," printed copy only, 1912 August 10 (Box 202, Folder 18)
    - Veto message of the House Army Appropriations Bill, final solution of problem and Henry Lewis Stimson statement, 1912 August 22-23 (Box 202, Folder 19)
    - Senate and House Bills and Reports, printed decisions, correspondence of others regarding navigable waterways and other waterpower issues, 1912 May 13 (Box 202, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence of others, memoranda, notes relating to miscellaneous administrative problems of the War Department, 1911-1913 (Box 202, Folder 21)
    - "Secretary Stimson's Administration of the War Department: A Review" by Felix Frankfurter and Captain George H. Shelton, 1913 March (Box 202, Folder 22)
  - World War I relief organizations
    - Commission for Relief in Belgium, 1915-1918 (Box 202, Folder 23-24)
    - American Red Cross, 1915-1917 (Box 202, Folder 25)
  - League of Nations
    - Talk with Elihu Root, letter: Root to House. Henry Lewis Stimson Analysis of salient points of League Constitution., 1918 August 16 (Box 202, Folder 26)
    - Republican Club of New York City, Committee on National Affairs, Sub-committee on Peace Treaty and Foreign Relations, Resolutions and proposed resolutions regarding the League of Nations, 1919 (Box 202, Folder 27)
  - Theodore Roosevelt Memorial Association, organizational material, 1919 (Box 202, Folder 28)
  - Constitutional Convention, 1915
    - General organizational material (Box 203, Folder 1)
    - Finance committee, minutes of meeting (Box 203, Folder 2)
    - Transcript: Appearances by Deputy Comptroller Wendell, A. C. Forbes, and Russell Wiggins before the Finance Committee, 1915 May 12 (Box 203, Folder 3)
    - Transcript: Appearance by Comptroller Prendergast before the Finance Committee, 1915 May 19 (Box 203, Folder 4)
    - Transcript: Appearances of State Treasurer James M. Wells and Comptroller Eugene L. Travis before a joint meeting..., 1915 May 25 (Box 203, Folder 5)
    - Transcript: Appearance by Mr. Fitzgerald and Mr. Adler before the Committee on State Finance, notes by Henry Lewis Stimson, 1915 May 26 (Box 203, Folder 6)
    - Transcript: Appearances by R. B. Smith, A. E. Smith, Homer Folks, and Mr. Kirkbride before the Committee on State Finance, 1915 June 16 (Box 203, Folder 7)
    - Transcript: Appearances by James W. Wadsworth and Elon R. Brown before the Committee on State Finance and Committee on Governor and Other State Officers, 1915 June 22 (Box 203, Folder 8)
    - Transcript: Appearance by Mr. Harris, George McAneny, and Henry M. Sage before Committee on State Finance, 1915 June 23 (Box 203, Folder 9)
    - Transcript: Appearance by ex-Governor Glynn before the Committee on State Finance, 1915 June 30 (Box 203, Folder 10)
    - Proposed Amendments before the State Finances Committee, 1915 April-August (Box 203, Folder 11)
    - Proposed Constitutional Amendment no. 716, 739 Int. 692, introduced by the Committee on State Finances to amend sections 2, 4, 5 of article VII of the Constitution..., 1915 June-July (Box 203, Folder 12)
    - Memoranda, aides-memoire, notes and other research material for the Finance Committee in relation to state debts, serial bonds, and sinking funds (Box 203, Folder 13)
    - Memoranda, aides-memoire, notes and other research material for the State Finance committee in relation to state debts, serial bonds, and sinking funds, 1915 April-July (Box 204, Folder 1)
    - State Finances Committee proposal for an annual budget, 1915 July-August (Box 204, Folder 2)
    - Compilations of Amendments Referred to the Committee on State Finance (Box 204, Folder 3)
    - Committee on Governor and Other State Officers, minutes and drafts of report to the committee, memoranda, notes, research material, 1915 April-August (Box 204, Folder 4-5)
    - Compilation of Amendments Referred to the Committee on Governor and Other State Officers (Box 204, Folder 6)
    - Committee on Judiciary, 1915 May-August (Box 204, Folder 7)
    - Compilation of Amendments Referred to Judiciary Committee I (Box 204, Folder 8)
    - Compilation of Amendments Referred to Committee on Judiciary II (Box 205, Folder 1)
    - Henry Lewis Stimson Notebook, Notes on Responsible Government, 1915 April-September (Box 205, Folder 2)
    - Constitutional Convention 1915-miscellaneous papers (Box 205, Folder 3)
    - Constitutional Convention 1914-miscellaneous papers (Box 205, Folder 4)
    - Constitutional Convention 1915, miscellaneous printed material, 1915 January-March (Box 205, Folder 5-6)
    - New York State Constitutional Convention 1915, miscellaneous printed material, 1915 April-September (Box 205, Folder 7)
    - Printed Proceedings of the New York Constitutional Convention, 8 volumes (Box 206)
    - Committee for Adoption of the Constitution, Committee on Finance, 1915 October-November (Box 205, Folder 9)
    - Committee for Adoption of the Constitution, drafts of propaganda leaflets and printed campaign material, 1915 September-November (Box 205, Folder 10-11)
    - Miscellaneous material from the campaign for Adoption of the New York State Constitution, 1915 September-November (Box 205, Folder 12)
    - Constitutional Convention, Reunion Dinner, Record of Proceedings, printed copy, 1926 December 17 (Box 205, Folder 13-14)
  - Preparedness organizations, 1915-1918
    - National Security League, 1915-1916 January (Box 207, Folder 1)
      See also: Series X, Printed Material, 1914-1917, boxes 251-252.
    - National Security League, 1916 February-1918 February (Box 207, Folder 2-4)
    - National Security League-pamphlets, 1915-1917 (Box 207, Folder 5)
    - National Security League, 1919-1920, 1926 (Box 207, Folder 6)
    - New York City Mayors Committee on National Defense, 1917 (Box 207, Folder 7)
    - Association for National Service, 1916 (Box 207, Folder 8)
    - National Association for Universal Military Training, 1917 (Box 207, Folder 9)
    - West Hills Rifle Club, 1917 (Box 207, Folder 10)
    - Selected Defense and Preparedness Organizations
      - American Rights Committee, 1916-1920 (Box 207, Folder 11)
      - Civic Federation, 1916-1920 (Box 207, Folder 11)
      - Conference Committee on National Preparedness, 1916-1920 (Box 207, Folder 11)
      - National Committee of Patriotic and Defense Societies, 1916-1920 (Box 207, Folder 11)
      - Universal Military Training League, 1916-1920 (Box 207, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence of others, memoranda, and reports regarding military organization and national defense (Box 207, Folder 12)
    - Roosevelt Division, 1916-1917 (Box 207, Folder 13)
    - Mobilization of the National Guard for Service on the Mexican Border, 1916 (Box 207, Folder 14)
  - Military service, 1917-1918
    - Military service, notes, memoranda, correspondence of others, 1916-1918 November (Box 208, Folder 1-2)
    - Clearance Certificates for 31st Field Artillery Members, 1918 (Box 208, Folder 3)
    - Book of officer rankings, 1918 (Box 208, Folder 3)
    - Wartime address book, 1918 (Box 208, Folder 3)
  - Postwar military organizations
    - Henry Lewis Stimson notes on Army Reorganization, [1919] (Box 208, Folder 4)
    - Seventy-seventh Division American Legion Posts Association, 1919-1921 (Box 208, Folder 5)
    - Committee for Aid to Disabled Veterans and Referendum on Bonus, 1920-1921 and related reference material regarding adjusted compensation plans (Box 208, Folder 6)
    - Ex-Service Men's Anti-Bonus League and related reference material regarding adjusted compensation bills, 1922-1924 (Box 208, Folder 7)
  - National Budget Committee 1919-1922 and reference material regarding national executive budget (Box 208, Folder 8)
  - Edward A. Rumely: Petition for Executive Clemency, 1924 (Box 208, Folder 9)
  - American Peace Award, 1923-1927
    - American Peace Award, 1923 June-1925 March 4 (Box 209, Folder 1-6)
    - American Foundation: Galley for International Law and International Relations, Circa 1925 September 1 (Box 209, Folder 7)
    - American Foundation: International Law and International Relations, 1925 September 1 (Box 209, Folder 8)
    - American Peace Award, 1925, pamphlets regarding the World Court (Box 209, Folder 9)
    - American Peace Award, 1926-1927 (Box 209, Folder 10)
  - New York State Reorganization Commission, 1925-1926
    - List of members on New York State Reorganization Commission, 1925 (Box 209, Folder 11)
    - Memoranda and other reference material regarding administrative organization of several states, 1925 December (Box 209, Folder 12)
    - Memoranda and other reference material regarding budgetary procedures of New York and various other states, 1925 November (Box 209, Folder 13)
    - Memos and preliminary reports of the sub-committee on the Executive and State Departments, 1925 December (Box 209, Folder 14)
    - Report of H.E. Machold and Henry Lewis Stimson as to Constitutional Budget, 1926 January 14 (Box 209, Folder 15)
    - Memos regarding problems in and revisions of the preliminary reports of the sub-committee on the Executive and State Departments, 1926 January-February (Box 209, Folder 16)
    - Final report of the sub-committee on the Executive and State Departments on the Executive Department, 1926 February 18 (Box 209, Folder 17)
    - Memoranda regarding committee to consider formation of a Department of Public Welfare, 1925 December-1926 January (Box 210, Folder 1)
    - Reports of various sub-committees of the State Reorganization Commission, 1925 December-1926 February (Box 210, Folder 2)
    - Drafts for new State Departments Law enacting changes proposed by the State Reorganization Commission, 1926 (Box 210, Folder 3)
    - Final Report of the subcommittee on the Executive and State Departments as to the Reorganization of the State Department, 1926 February 18 (Box 210, Folder 4)